<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Mark's RC Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Pellentesque odio nisi, euismod in, pharetra a, ultricies in, diam. Sed arcu.]]></description><link>https://emceelamb.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 01:37:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Day 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I joined a reading group about Haskell programming langage.]]></description><link>https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day03</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day03</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I joined a reading group about Haskell programming language. It was the first meeting to go through UPenn’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seas.upenn.edu/%7Ecis194/spring13/lectures.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;CIS-194: Introduction to Haskell&lt;/a&gt;. The group plans to work through the course throughout the batch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a group we tried paired reading. We each partnered up to read the first chapter and took turns reading out loud paragraphs from the book. While reading the paragraphs we would check in and talk about any unclear sections. My reading partner, Daniel, had some experience with Haskell before, so he gave a lot of good insight into the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t have too much experience with functional programming paradigm. I’ve done a little functional javascript programming, and worked through Understanding the Weird Parts of Javascript, which gave an introduction to the paradigm, but I don’t regularly use it. However, it was pretty influential as I progressed through my programming journey as it helped me break out of a purely OOP approach to programming and learning to take a more functional approach which allows or cleaner looking code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction to the course gave a broad overview of the Haskell language and some of its features. TBF the syntax is very different to what I am used to. Its akin to clojure which I briefly sampled before. The last programming language I’ve been learning is C, and Haskell is quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll try to stick with the group for a bit, but I’m on the fence with how far I will go with it though. My goal for RC is to come away with employable skills, and from what I read, Haskell is not seen often commercially. I’ve been wanting to learn Go, so I might stick with that? But maybe just learning Haskell and FP will be beneficial overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a fun video that makes me want to learn haskell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot; &gt; &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RqvCNb7fKsg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Day 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I revisited old computer setups and was plagued by technical problems.]]></description><link>https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day02</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day02</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I only came to my apartment a handful of times since Covid quarantine started back in March. I was staying at a friend’s house with my school laptop that I’ve been working on. My personal laptop and my desktop machine was left collecting dust until I moved back in late last night. So today I dusted them off and booted them up for the first time in quite a while and thought a lot about computers as I did so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-about-my-computing-set-up&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-little-about-my-computing-set-up&quot; aria-label=&quot;a little about my computing set up permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A little about my computing set up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My school laptop is a very beefy ASUS ROG gaming laptop that I revived from the ITP junk shelf. I picked it up about a year ago and replaced the battery, charger, and installed Arch Linux (btw I use Arch) and it was working great, but over the past year the battery has rapidly lost health, and only holds charge for ~15 minutes. Pretty disappointing after spending about $60 for a replacement last year. Recently, it has been prone to freezing due to memory depletion. Anyways, I like the environment very much since I’ve been customizing my configs over the past year and it has been my primary developing machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I started leaving my ASUS at school, my personal computer was my every day machine. It’s a Dell inspiron, that is pretty light and nice. It runs Windows 10 and has lot of media making programs on it such as Ableton, Max, Adobe, C4D, and etc. When I was in school and started developing, I would install a Linux OS to an external hard drive, and develop mostly on that. I kind of liked that setup, but the external hd was prone to corrupting, and damage which is not great. I had to wipe and reinstall a couple of times. I did this because I didn’t have a lot of space on my SSD, and retrospectively I should still partition my SSD and use my external hd for storage instead of completely installing the OS to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My desktop set up was built for rendering and video production a long time ago. At the time it was pretty specced, but now the hardware is a bit dated. I’ve since installed  Ubuntu 18.04 and occasionally will work on it. I like it because it is still better than my laptops, and desktops are comfortable, although not portable. Over the years though my RAM has been problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;booting-them&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#booting-them&quot; aria-label=&quot;booting them permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Booting them&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My desktop was incredibly finicky when I began on it. It booted fine, but 10 minutes in, it went kaput. My ASROCK Dr Debug kept showing crazy error codes around memory. First error 53 meaning memory can not initialize, and later error 55 no memory found. I tried reseating my RAM sticks, tried different configurations, until it finally worked. I’m only using one stick now though in the third slot. I then updated my computer, and tweaked my configs again to make it more comfortable. I hope to use it more often again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT the wifi stopped working on it, which is still not yet resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tailwind&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#tailwind&quot; aria-label=&quot;tailwind permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tailwind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working on my computer for a while, I began working on an ongoing project where I am learning Tailwindd CSS. I really enjoy working with tailwind. It definitely is more fun and faster to develop than writing a lot of css. I also like the ability write styles as needed though. I’m still learning more intricacies around tailwind but hopefully later I’ll write a post about tailwind css and how it differs other css frameworks like Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;epilog-nand2tetris&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#epilog-nand2tetris&quot; aria-label=&quot;epilog nand2tetris permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Epilog NAND2Tetris?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After laboring on the hardware of my machine for so long I’m thinking about doing nand2tetris as a rc project. I think it would be really cool to learn more in-depth how these machines operate. I think the only concern is about how practical that endeavor would be. One of my goals for rc is to pick up employable skills, so I’m not sure how that might factor in. Something to ask around I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Day 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I attended a pair programming workshop and moved my apartment into storage.]]></description><link>https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day01</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day01</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today at RC I attended a pair programming workshop where a couple of summer 2 recursers talked about common tips for pair programming. They then showed us Repl.it’s collaborative environment. We then got partnered with another rc-er and tried it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pairing session was to build a game of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mastermind_(board_game)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Mastermind&lt;/a&gt;. My partner and I decided to use Javascript for our programming language. While talking about the rules of the game, we loosely  broke down things we needed to accomplish. We both didn’t have a lot of experience using Node.js and in the console, so we ended  up having to look up documentation for a lot of things such as reading console input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we began fleshing out the application we would run into issues with quirks of javascript as the language didn’t exactly match our mental model. For instance, we wanted to run the game in a while loop, but readline in node is async so it couldn’t be in a while loop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We switched between navigator and driver pretty regularly, basically for every step we would swap. Small things like generating a code, and reading an input warranted switching. I liked switching often because it allowed for a more synthesized application instead of by a single mind. Also since we were so often looking up documentation, it allowed for a lot of natural pauses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t complete the game in the 30 minute session, but it was a lot of fun and it was great to work with someone to see how they tackle problems and find solutions. View our &lt;a href=&quot;https://repl.it/@Emceelamb/StupidFeistyDecagon#index.js&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;repl.it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the pairing workshop, I helped my friend move their apartment into storage, so I didn’t get too much done.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Day 0]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today was my first day at Recurse Center! It was an interesting to learn more about the programming community that I heard a lot about, and particularly how they have adapted to the ongoing Covid-19 Pandemic.]]></description><link>https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://emceelamb.github.io/posts/day0</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today was my first day at &lt;a href=&quot;https://recurse.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt;! It was an interesting to learn more about the programming community that I heard a lot about, and particularly how they have adapted to the ongoing Covid-19 Pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-recurse-center-rc&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-is-recurse-center-rc&quot; aria-label=&quot;what is recurse center rc permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is Recurse Center (RC)?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RC describes itself as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Recurse Center is a self-directed, community-driven educational retreat for programmers based in New York City and currently operating online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is in line with a writer’s retreat, but for programmers. People from different stages come to RC in order to improve their skills. Participants can commit to a Mini Batch (1 Week), a Half Batch (6 Weeks), and a Full batch (12 Weeks). I signed up for a half batch because I’m not sure of my near future plans, and RC allows you to extend to a full batch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-am-i-going-to-rc-after-spending-2-years-at-itp&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-am-i-going-to-rc-after-spending-2-years-at-itp&quot; aria-label=&quot;why am i going to rc after spending 2 years at itp permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why am I going to rc after spending 2 years at ITP?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITP was a great playground to for making technology projects, but it lacked rigor for technical projects. So while I was exposed to many different applications for technology, I wanted to understand how software/hardware works at a deeper level. I’m using my time at RC to brush up on hard skills especially for applying to jobs in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;virtual-rc&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#virtual-rc&quot; aria-label=&quot;virtual rc permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Virtual RC?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to COVID-19 RC is running all their batches online, but they have made interesting ways to adjust to the online medium. RC created a virtual map of their office, and use zoom as a way to mimic the IRL experience. At this point in covid, I’m pretty accustom with virtual environments, so it gets easier meeting new people over video chat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An advantage of doing virtual rc is that people from all over the world are able to attend. A list of my batch mates include: Vancouver, Seattle, SF, NY, London, France, India, and Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-day&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-first-day&quot; aria-label=&quot;the first day permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The first day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was the first day, and it was mostly on-boarding. Facilitators presented about the social rules of RC, and demoed some of the software tools that virtual rc runs on. I attended a couple of interesting sessions such as an RFC chat, where there was a discussion of the RFC which defined the SMTP email protocol. Another session was about front end development work flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When meeting some of my batch mates, a lot of discussion was around projects and plans for the batch. Mini retreat participants only have a week to work on a project, so many of them have projects pretty clearly defined. Other participants seem to have projects they are working on, and others seem to have subject areas that they want to work on such as becoming more versed at the front-end pipeline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for me, I’m not entirely sure. I answered to many people that I want to work on making a homelab for network experimentation, but I don’t really know to what end it will be. Mostly I want to work on learning the devops pipeline, but I don’t know how to approach it quite yet. During the next few days I want to make more of a study plan to be more focused during my batch.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>